MoMA PS1 Archives
The Museum of Modern Art, Publisher
- Series I: Curatorial and Exhibition Records, (19682009)
  - Subseries I.A: General Files, (19702009)
    - Competition Diomede Glenn Weiss Received Correspondence, 1988-1989; Received correspondence, most requesting competition information and application materials. Here and There: Travels, Part IV: Competition Diomede(May 18-July 2, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 77, Folder I.A.1398)
    - Competition Diomede Photographs and Press Releases, 1989; Here and There: Travels, Part IV: Competition Diomede(May 18-July 2, 1989): Press Release; Art and Event Photographs (Box 77, Folder I.A.1399)
    - Competition Diomede Submissions, 1989; Submission materials, sketches, plans, and images from multiple individuals and groups. Here and There: Travels, Part IV: Competition Diomede(May 18-July 2, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 77, Folder I.A.1400)
    - Competition Diomede Submissions, 1989; Submission materials, sketches, plans, and images from multiple individuals and groups. Here and There: Travels, Part IV: Competition Diomede(May 18-July 2, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 78, Folder I.A.1401)
    - Competition Diomede Submissions, 1989; Submission materials, sketches, plans, and images from multiple individuals and groups. Here and There: Travels, Part IV: Competition Diomede(May 18-July 2, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 78, Folder I.A.1402)
    - "Diomedes-Architect", 1988; Small amount of material only. Here and There: Travels, Part IV: Competition Diomede(May 18-July 2, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 78, Folder I.A.1403)
    - Competition Diomede, 1988-1999; Includes some correspondence. Here and There: Travels, Part IV: Competition Diomede(May 18-July 2, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 78, Folder I.A.1404)
    - "Clocktower: Diomede", 1994-1995; Small amount of correspondence only. Here and There: Travels, Part IV: Competition Diomede(May 18-July 2, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 78, Folder I.A.1405)
    - "Architecture", 1989; Proposal by Glenn Weiss, with notes and other planning documents for the "Exhibition Diomedes." Also includes a NEA grant proposal by Glenn Weiss for a conference and exhibition titled "Unseen Architecture." Here and There: Travels, Part IV: Competition Diomede(May 18-July 2, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation; The documents in this folder have been severely damaged by water; patrons must use gloves when handling these materials. (Box 78, Folder I.A.1406)
    - Marie-Jose Burki Portfolio, 1989-1990; Contains photographs of video stills and video installations. (Box 78, Folder I.A.1407)
    - Miscellaneous Artists' Portfolios, circa 1990; Includes miscellaneous slides, CVs, clippings, price lists, and gallery materials. (Box 78, Folder I.A.1408)
    - Miscellaneous Artists' Portfolios, 1989-1990; Includes miscellaneous slides, CVs, clippings, price lists, and gallery materials. (Box 78, Folder I.A.1409)
    - Miscellaneous Clocktower Materials, 1989-1990; Mainly related to exhibitions and activities in 1989. (Box 78, Folder I.A.1410)
    - Dieter Roth, circa 1989; Artist's CV, three artwork slides, and a letter from Nam June Paik to Roth mentioning another letter from Alanna Heiss and Chris Dercon (not present) presumably proposing an exhibition of Roth's work. (Box 78, Folder I.A.1411)
    - "Press Releases for Fall", 1989 (Box 78, Folder I.A.1412)
    - "Fall 1989", Miscellaneous notes and memos, installation schedules, biographical materials and other documents pertaining the fall (Box 78, Folder I.A.1413)
    - "Clocktower 1989-1990 Periphery", Small amount of documents concerning the exhibition schedule for the season. (Box 78, Folder I.A.1414)
    - Giancarlo Neri Slides, 1989; Images of Neri's photographs, along with unlabelled, possibly unrelated, installation shots of different photographs. Giancarlo Neri: "Still Night"(September 28-October 15, 1989): Art and Event Photographs (Box 79, Folder I.A.1415)
    - "Gursky/Struth/Giancarlo Neri", 1989; Background material on the artists with some correspondence and press materials. Giancarlo Neri: "Still Night"(September 28-October 15, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation The Periphery, Part I: Andreas Gursky and Thomas Struth(September 28-November 5, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 79, Folder I.A.1416)
    - "Part I, Struth and Gursky", 1989; Small amount of material only. The Periphery, Part I: Andreas Gursky and Thomas Struth(September 28-November 5, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 79, Folder I.A.1417)
    - Thomas Struth and Andreas Gursky, 1990; Two sheets of exhibition history and an annotated checklist. The Periphery, Part I: Andreas Gursky and Thomas Struth(September 28-November 5, 1989): Checklist; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 79, Folder I.A.1418)
    - Thomas Struth and Andreas Gursky, 1989; Includes two press packets of Ruhr Works an exhibition held by Goethe House, New York, and to which the Gursky and Struth exhibition was related. The Periphery, Part I: Andreas Gursky and Thomas Struth(September 28-November 5, 1989): Press Release (Box 79, Folder I.A.1419)
    - Ruhr Works, 1989; Catalogue on German arts published by the Goethe House, NY. (Box 79, Folder I.A.1420)
    - "Three French Artists", 1989; Includes installation information, budget, and other materials. Andr Cadere (1934-1978)(October 15-December 10, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation Catherine Beaugrand(October 15-December 10, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation Raymond Hains(October 15-December 10, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 79, Folder I.A.1421)
    - "Three French Artists", 1989; Mainly correspondence concerning the exhibitions. Andr Cadere (1934-1978)(October 15-December 10, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation Catherine Beaugrand(October 15-December 10, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation Raymond Hains(October 15-December 10, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 79, Folder I.A.1422)
    - "Andr Cadere Publication", 1991-1992; Primarily correspondence. Andr Cadere (1934-1978)(October 15-December 10, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 79, Folder I.A.1423)
    - "Andr Cadere", 1989-1990; Includes correspondence, budget, copious notes and other materials. Some materials refer to this exhibition as "Three French Artists" though it was later split into three separate shows. Andr Cadere (1934-1978)(October 15-December 10, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 79, Folder I.A.1424)
    - "French Projects", 1988-2989; Includes multi-page description of an exhibition about the Situationist International (SI) group of artists and it's possible showing at P.S. 1. (Box 79, Folder I.A.1425)
    - "Three French Artists" Travel Plans and Address Lists, 1989; The documents in this folder have been severely damaged by water; patrons must use gloves when handling these materials. (Box 79, Folder I.A.1426)
    - "1988-1989 Loan Forms and Insurance: 3 French Artists", Insurance materials only. Andr Cadere (1934-1978)(October 15-December 10, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation Catherine Beaugrand(October 15-December 10, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation Raymond Hains(October 15-December 10, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 80, Folder I.A.1427)
    - "Returns, Shipping, Condition Reports Tour 1989: Three French Artists Shipping", With correspondence regarding loans and returns. Andr Cadere (1934-1978)(October 15-December 10, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation Catherine Beaugrand(October 15-December 10, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation Raymond Hains(October 15-December 10, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Shipping and insurance documents. (Box 80, Folder I.A.1428)
    - "1988-1989 Loan Forms and Insurance: Three French Artists", Includes installation floor plans. Andr Cadere (1934-1978)(October 15-December 10, 1989): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Catherine Beaugrand(October 15-December 10, 1989): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Raymond Hains(October 15-December 10, 1989): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Entire folder restricted. (Box 80, Folder I.A.1429)
    - British Exhibition Proposal, 1989; Exhibition proposal for a group of five British artists including Chris Gallacio and Tim Wright.; The documents in this folder have been severely damaged by water; patrons must use gloves when handling these materials. (Box 80, Folder I.A.1430)
    - Victoria Vesna Correspondence, 1989; One card and postcard.; The documents in this folder have been severely damaged by water; patrons must use gloves when handling these materials. (Box 80, Folder I.A.1431)
    - "Program Schedules and Listings", 1989-1990 (Box 80, Folder I.A.1432)
    - Rod Rhodes Artwork Photographs, 1989; Images of artworks and objects by Rhodes related to his memorial exhibition. The Periphery, Part II: Rod Rhodes and Paul Thek(November 16-December 24, 1989): Art and Event Photographs (Box 80, Folder I.A.1433)
    - Rod Rhodes Artwork Photographs, 1989; Images of artworks and objects by Rhodes related to his memorial exhibition. The Periphery, Part II: Rod Rhodes and Paul Thek(November 16-December 24, 1989): Art and Event Photographs (Box 80, Folder I.A.1434)
    - "Rhodes Travel", 1988-1990; Includes correspondence and other exhibition documentation, as well as material relating to other venues. The Periphery, Part II: Rod Rhodes and Paul Thek(November 16-December 24, 1989): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Loan forms, exhibition contracts, and insurance documents. (Box 80, Folder I.A.1435)
    - Paul Thek, 1989; Includes numerous slides of Thek's work. The Periphery, Part II: Rod Rhodes and Paul Thek(November 16-December 24, 1989): Art and Event Photographs; Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Restricted material removed: Loan forms. (Box 80, Folder I.A.1436)
    - "The Clocktower: The Periphery", 1988; News clippings, correspondence, and other docuements. The Periphery, Part II: Rod Rhodes and Paul Thek(November 16-December 24, 1989): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 80, Folder I.A.1437)
    - Seasonal Brochures and Ephemera, 1989-1990; Includes multiple brochures, the poster for Positive Actions: Visual AIDS Competition, and the catalogue/brochure for Casin Fantasma. Casin Fantasma(May 24-July 15, 1990): Printed Ephemera CommuNYCations: Positive Actions: Visual AIDS Competition(November 29, 1990-January 20, 1991): Printed Ephemera (Box 81, Folder I.A.1438)
    - Stephen Prina, 1989-1990; Includes sketch of installation map, contracts, partial checklists, materials related to prior locations of the exhibition, artwork descriptions, and other materials. Stephen Prina: Monochrome Painting(January 14-March 11, 1990): Checklist; Printed Ephemera; General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Exhibition contracts, insurance documents, and loan forms. (Box 81, Folder I.A.1439)
    - "Returns, Shipping, Condition Reports Tour 1989: Prina/Hafif", 1989-1990; Marcia Hafif(January 14-March 11, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation Stephen Prina: Monochrome Painting(January 14-March 11, 1990): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; General Exhibition Documentation; Entire folder restricted. (Box 81, Folder I.A.1440)
    - Forced Out, 1989; Small amount of correspondence. Forced Out: The Agony of the Refugee in Our Time(January 14-March 11, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 81, Folder I.A.1441)
    - "Refugees Winter", 1989; Mainly promotional material from the publisher of the catalogue. Forced Out: The Agony of the Refugee in Our Time(January 14-March 11, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 81, Folder I.A.1442)
    - Forced Out, 1990; Includes budget materials and some correspondence. Forced Out: The Agony of the Refugee in Our Time(January 14-March 11, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 81, Folder I.A.1443)
    - "Returns, Shipping, Condition Reports Tour 1989:Forced Out", Includes installation documents and lists of captions for artworks. Forced Out: The Agony of the Refugee in Our Time(January 14-March 11, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Shipping documents. (Box 81, Folder I.A.1444)
    - Alan Saret, 1989; Extensive photocopies of artworks with notes, with correspondence and some loan forms. Alan Saret(January 14-March 11, 1990): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Loan forms. (Box 81, Folder I.A.1445)
    - "Alan Saret Collectors", 1989-1990; Correspondence, loan forms, and printout of information for wall cards, with notes on installation placement. Alan Saret(January 14-March 11, 1990): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Loan forms and insurance documents. (Box 81, Folder I.A.1446)
    - "Alan Saret: Extras", 1990; Articles and background material. Includes a color photograph of Fifth Solar Chthonic Wall Temple from Rooms, signed "To the 'Clocktower' people with Love, Alan." Rooms(June 9-June 26, 1976): Installation Photographs Alan Saret(January 14-March 11, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 81, Folder I.A.1447)
    - "Alan Saret: Reviews, Articles", 1990; Alan Saret(January 14-March 11, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 81, Folder I.A.1448)
    - "Alan Saret: Catalogue Information", 1990; Annotated manuscript of publicity release for the exhibition catalogue. Alan Saret(January 14-March 11, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 81, Folder I.A.1449)
    - Alan Saret, 1989; Small amount of correspondence and transparencies of artworks, along with selections of Saret's writings. Alan Saret(January 14-March 11, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 81, Folder I.A.1450)
    - "Alan Saret Collectors: Dan Weinberg", 1989-1990; Includes numerous slides and transparencies of Saret's work, along with some correspondence with Weinberg. Alan Saret(January 14-March 11, 1990): Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 82, Folder I.A.1451)
    - "Alan Saret Collectors: Mr. and Mrs. Augusta and Benno Westheim", 1989-1990; Correspondence with some loan forms and photocopies of images. Alan Saret(January 14-March 11, 1990): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Loan forms. (Box 82, Folder I.A.1452)
    - Alana Saret, 1989-1990; Lists of works from specific lenders and draft label texts Alan Saret(January 14-March 11, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 82, Folder I.A.1453)
    - "Alan Saret: Untitled and Titled Projects Winter 1990", Slides of installations and artworks from Saret's 1990 exhibition, of his works in Images of the Unknown, and of artworks from 1985 to 1986. Image and Object in Contemporary Sculpture(December 9, 1979-January 27, 1980): Installation Photographs; Art and Event Photographs Alan Saret(January 14-March 11, 1990): Installation Photographs (Box 82, Folder I.A.1454)
    - "General Exhibition Papers: Alan Saret", 1990; Working checklists, installation maps, and "certificates of title" describing individual artworks and handling instructions. Alan Saret(January 14-March 11, 1990): Checklist; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 82, Folder I.A.1455)
    - "Returns, Shipping, Condition Reports Tour 1989: Saret Shipping", Includes loan correspondence. Alan Saret(January 14-March 11, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Shipping and insurance documents. (Box 82, Folder I.A.1456)
    - Marcia Hafif, 1989; Some correspondence, with articles and writings by the artist, one ("For Dieter Villinger") in manuscript. Marcia Hafif(January 14-March 11, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 82, Folder I.A.1457)
    - "Hafif/Prina/Saret", 1988-1989; Includes text of essay on Alan Saret as well as scattered materials on other exhibitions at the Clocktower. Alan Saret(January 14-March 11, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 82, Folder I.A.1458)
    - "1989-1990 Loan Forms and Insurance: Hafif/Prina/Saret/Forced Out", Alan Saret(January 14-March 11, 1990): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Forced Out: The Agony of the Refugee in Our Time(January 14-March 11, 1990): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Marcia Hafif(January 14-March 11, 1990): Loan Forms and Condition Reports Stephen Prina: Monochrome Painting(January 14-March 11, 1990): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Entire folder restricted. (Box 82, Folder I.A.1459)
    - The Periphery, Part III, 1989; Correspondence, information on the artists, slides, and original proposals for the exhibition from Nam Jun Paik describing his conception of the exhibition and his own contributions to the show. The Periphery, Part III: Video Spin-Offs(January 18-February 25, 1990): Art and Event Photographs; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 82, Folder I.A.1460)
    - "CT-Periphery III: Paik, Heske, Connors, Garin", 1990-1991; Documents relating to shipping. The Periphery, Part III: Video Spin-Offs(January 18-February 25, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Shipping documents, exhibition contracts, and loan documents. (Box 82, Folder I.A.1461)
    - "Pail, Connor, Garrin, Heske", 1990; Numerous photographs and slides of works by the artists, some may be actual installation views; also includes notes and correspondence, insurance forms, and installation sketches. The Periphery, Part III: Video Spin-Offs(January 18-February 25, 1990): Art and Event Photographs (Box 82, Folder I.A.1462)
    - Eleanor Bond, 1989; Includes some correspondence, lists of loans, and biographical material. The Periphery, Part IV: Eleanor Bond and Kiki Smith(March 15-April 22, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 83, Folder I.A.1463)
    - "Part IV", 1989; Two pieces of correspondence only. The Periphery, Part IV: Eleanor Bond and Kiki Smith(March 15-April 22, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 83, Folder I.A.1464)
    - Kiki Smith, 1989; News clippings and biographical material mainly, with one photocopy of an installation proposal. The Periphery, Part IV: Eleanor Bond and Kiki Smith(March 15-April 22, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 83, Folder I.A.1465)
    - "Clocktower Projects", 1990; Correspondence and contracts regarding Eleanor Bond's work for the exhibition. The Periphery, Part IV: Eleanor Bond and Kiki Smith(March 15-April 22, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 83, Folder I.A.1466)
    - "Bond/Smith", 1990; Correspondence, with some relating to damage to Bond's works. The Periphery, Part IV: Eleanor Bond and Kiki Smith(March 15-April 22, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 83, Folder I.A.1467)
    - "Asian American Arts Chinese Political Project", 1990; Includes correspondence, some artist agreements, photographs, and other documents. China - June 4, 1989(April 22-June 17, 1990): Checklist; Installation Photographs; News Clippings; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 83, Folder I.A.1468)
    - "China Lists", 1989-1990; Various materials regarding the commemorative exhibition including lists of participants and correspondence. China - June 4, 1989(April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 83, Folder I.A.1469)
    - "General Exhibition Papers: China Show", 1990; Includes some correspondence. China - June 4, 1989(April 22-June 17, 1990): Checklist; General Exhibition Documentation (Box 83, Folder I.A.1470)
    - "1990-1991 Loan Forms and Insurance: China Show", Checklist of works with insurance values only. China - June 4, 1989(April 22-June 17, 1990): Checklist; General Exhibition Documentation; Entire folder restricted. (Box 83, Folder I.A.1471)
    - "Returns, Shipping, Condition Reports Tour 1990": Unknown Exhibition, Pick-up and return receipts with notes; possibly related to following folder.; Entire folder restricted. (Box 83, Folder I.A.1472)
    - "Returns, Shipping, Condition Reports Tour 1990: China, Special Projects", Includes some correspondence and installation information. China - June 4, 1989(April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Shipping documents. (Box 83, Folder I.A.1473)
    - "Special Projects", 1988-1989; Lists of participating artists from winter 1989 and spring 1990 and a checklist of 1990 artworks and their insurance value.; Restricted material removed: Insurance checklists. (Box 83, Folder I.A.1474)
    - Special Projects (Spring 1990): Daina Shobrys, 1989; Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 83, Folder I.A.1475)
    - Special Projects (Spring 1990): Brandon Krall, 1988; Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 83, Folder I.A.1476)
    - Special Projects (Spring 1990): Catherine Howe, 1988; Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 83, Folder I.A.1477)
    - Special Projects (Spring 1990): Michael Corris, Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 83, Folder I.A.1478)
    - Special Projects (Spring 1990): "Contracts and Loan", Includes list of participating artists, contracts, and some correspondence. Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 83, Folder I.A.1479)
    - Special Projects (Spring 1990): Kevin Carter, Includes sketches of installation proposal. Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 83, Folder I.A.1480)
    - "Special Projects", 1990; Correspondence with some shipping documents. Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation; Restricted material removed: Shipping documents. (Box 83, Folder I.A.1481)
    - Special Projects (Spring 1990): Willie Cole, Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 84, Folder I.A.1482)
    - Special Projects (Spring 1990): Janet Zweig, Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 84, Folder I.A.1483)
    - Special Projects (Spring 1990): Antonello Piemontese, Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 84, Folder I.A.1484)
    - Special Projects (Spring 1990): Installation Map, Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 84, Folder I.A.1485)
    - Special Projects (Spring 1990): Danny Tisdale, Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 84, Folder I.A.1486)
    - Special Projects (Spring 1990): Beverly Semmes, Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 84, Folder I.A.1487)
    - Special Projects (Spring 1990): Heidi Schlatter, Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 84, Folder I.A.1488)
    - Special Projects (Spring 1990): "A.T.W. [Around the World]", Includes extensive promotional materials on the group. Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): General Exhibition Documentation (Box 84, Folder I.A.1489)
    - "1990-1991 Loan Forms and Insurance: Special Projects", Special Projects (Spring 1990) (April 22-June 17, 1990): Loan Forms and Condition Reports; Entire folder restricted. (Box 84, Folder I.A.1490)
    - "Studio Show 1990", List of studio exhibitions and studio participants from 1976 to 1989.; The documents in this folder have been severely damaged by water; patrons must use gloves when handling these materials. (Box 84, Folder I.A.1491)